{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Liquid flow rate is measured using,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Orifice Plate",
        "b": "Pirani Gauge",
        "c": "Pyrometer",
        "d": "Bourdon Tube"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Orifices are used to measure",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Velocity",
        "b": "Rate of flow",
        "c": "Pressure",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Bernoulliâ€™s Equation is a mathematical expression of ______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The ratio of kinetic to viscous forces in a flow stream",
        "b": "Potential and kinetic energies in a flow stream",
        "c": "Fluid density and compressibility in a restriction",
        "d": "Vertical height and pressure for a static fluid"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. For a linear time invariant system, an optimal controller can be designed if _____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The system is controllable and observable",
        "b": "The system is uncontrollable but stable",
        "c": "The system is unstable but observable",
        "d": "The system is stable but unobservable"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The function of the proportional mode is to ____________?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Provide Gain",
        "b": "Eliminate Offsets",
        "c": "To speed up the response and minimize the overshoot",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "6. The function of the proportional plus integral mode is to ____________?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Provide Gain",
        "b": "Eliminate Offsets",
        "c": "To speed up the response and minimize the overshoot",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },	
	
	{
      "question": "7. The feed forward control system ________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cannot make corrections until a measurable error exists",
        "b": "Is theoretically capable of perfect control",
        "c": "Makes a change in output that is the integrated error",
        "d": "Requires little knowledge of the process before installation"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
		
	{
      "question": "8. Which of the following statements is correct?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "By properly designing the PI controller, it is possible to make the transient response to a step input exhibit relatively small or no overshoot.",
        "b": "The PI controller is a lag compensator.",
        "c": "The characteristic of the PI controller is infinite gain at zero frequency.",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "9. In a single tank system, the transfer function of __________ to inlet flow rate is 1/TS+1.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Level",
        "b": "Outlet flow rate",
        "c": "Both of the above",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "10. __________ controller has the maximum stabilising time.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "P",
        "b": "PI",
        "c": "PID",
        "d": "PD"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
	
  ]
}